BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
[♪ opening theme song playing]
EPISODE 31:
SOMEWHERE SHE'D LIKE
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE ETWAS MOUNTAINS,
LOCATED IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
♪
[birds chirping]
[Stark grunts softly]
I didn't expect it to get
so warm and sunny
this far north.
We are in a volcanic area.
This region is known
for its unusual warmth.
That means we're getting close
to the hot springs, right?
Indeed.
I imagine the next town
will have a fine place to soak.
I look forward to taking a dip.
♪
-[footsteps]
-[rustling]
[STARK] Hey, Frieren,
we've been walking for a while.
We at least getting close?
[FRIEREN] Hmm...
We should be coming upon
the village any second now.
[bird cawing]
[FERN] Look, there's a cabin.
[FRIEREN] A solitary dwelling.
I have a bad feeling about this.
[children laughing]
[BOY 1] Don't be
a slow poke, mister!
[BOY 2] Hurry up! Hurry up!
-[laughter]
-[STARK] Wait for me!
This brings back old memories.
The village you're looking for
was abandoned.
It's been crumbling
for over 30 years.
When the hot spring dried,
the adventurers with big purses
stopped passing through.
So close, Mistress,
yet so far.
The moment you think
you know a human settlement,
it always gets
wiped clean off the map.
Suppose our dreams
will have to wait
-until we reach the next town.
-[STARK] Gotcha.
So, how long you think
it's gonna take us to get there?
A week's journey
at the very least.
But that's going to feel
like an eternity.
There must be another hot spring
hiding somewhere out here.
[FRIEREN] Hmm.
[MAN] Come to think of it,
my grandfather
used to tell a tall tale
of a hidden hot spring
tucked deep within
the nearby mountains.
Though, that would've been
well over thirty years ago.
The hidden spring
of the Etwas Mountains.
[STARK] Hm.
So you've heard of it before?
Yes, but I'm doubtful
it still exists.
And it would be tricky
to find out.
If our goal is to reach
a hot spring quickly,
we would be better off
heading to the next village.
[FERN] Uh...
What's that face, Mr. Stark?
The hidden spring
of the Etwas Mountains.
For some reason, I'm certain
I've heard that name before.
Oh.
I remember now.
Frieren, I think I'd like to
make the trip,
if that's all right with you.
Are you sure?
Allow me to warn you, Stark.
It's a hot spring
in the technical sense,
but I can assure you
it's not worth the trouble.
After all--
We're already
in the middle of nowhere.
Let's go check it out.
[Stark chuckles softly]
Goodness, Stark.
If your heart is set on it,
I suppose mine can follow.
[BOY 1] Bye-bye, mister!
Good luck out there!
[BOY 2] Come back
and play anytime!
[STARK] You two be good!
♪
A legendary spring is near.
Mistress Frieren?
I really figured you'd be
more excited right now.
Alas...
I wandered this same wood
with the others.
My joy was even more
tempered back then.
[HEITER] Mmm.
We should turn back.
[EISEN] Agreed.
You came here before?
And Mr. Himmel led
the charge? Why?
Himmel was equally curious
and thorough.
He wasn't satisfied
until he felt he'd explored
every nook and cranny
of a place.
You promised short and quick,
yet gave us long and grueling!
-[Heiter grunts]
-I'm telling you,
there's something here,
Heiter.
I could feel it in my soul!
Just trust me.
They should've listened to us.
[EISEN] There's no
turning back now.
♪
[FRIEREN] The road
to the hidden spring
grows increasingly brutal.
At some point, you have to
pass through the territory
of a troublesome monster.
♪
[distant roaring]
Seems "some point" is now.
Get ready.
[grunting]
[monster roars]
A dragon?
It's been a minute.
[FRIEREN] That's no dragon.
I would wager that pest
has more in common
with an ordinary lizard.
[STARK] Guess we'll find out.
[FERN] It looks so agitated.
[FRIEREN]
Wouldn't you be agitated
if a trio of fools
invaded your home?
If we fail to sever
all three heads
at the exact same time,
they'll regenerate.
You've gotta be kidding!
[Stark gasps]
[roaring]
-[FRIEREN] You run, Stark.
-[exclaims]
I've devised a genius plan.
What kind of plan starts...
[gasps]
[growling]
[Stark screaming]
[Stark panting]
You and I split up
to the left and right,
giving us each a head.
Got it.
I would prefer to get this right
on our first try.
[FERN] Hm.
If our timing is off,
it'll regenerate,
and our work will be undone.
So...
The genius plan
that you mentioned before...
We strike the beast
while it's busy playing
with our dear companion, Stark.
-[Stark screaming]
-[FERN] You mean...
[STARK]
You used me as live bait.
That, I did. Good work, you two.
♪
[Stark sighs]
-[Fern pants]
-[Stark grunts]
At least we made it here alive.
Perhaps, but just barely.
See? I tried to tell you
it would be better
to journey to the next town.
There lies the hidden
hot spring of legend.
It's so shallow.
[FERN] This is just a footbath.
[FRIEREN] Don't say
I didn't warn you.
[STARK] A footbath is fine.
This way, we can
enjoy it together.
[both chuckle softly]
[FRIEREN] That's true.
My, what a nice view.
Yeah.
Now that we've made it up here,
why were you so eager
to come in the first place?
'Cause my master told me
about this spot.
[EISEN] The famed hidden spring
of the Etwas Mountains
was a mere footbath.
We wasted a painful amount
of time getting there.
It was
a truly ridiculous adventure.
♪
[EISEN] As useless
as many of them were,
those ridiculous adventures
are the ones I reflect on most.
I wouldn't trade the memories of
those moments with my friends
for anything.
And I will never forget
that view.
♪
[FERN] So you knew
there was no real hot spring.
[STARK] I think I wanted to see
the same view my master saw.
♪
[STARK]
I'll never forget it, either.
[Fern grunts, thuds]
[Stark screams]
-[thudding]
-[Stark grunts]
[Stark groans]
The way back is worse
than the way here.
[Stark groans]
[STARK] I hope the memory
turns out sweeter
than the actual moment.
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE FORTRESS CITY OF HEIß,
LOCATED IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
♪
[Frieren sighs]
[WOMAN]
You sure love hot springs
for someone so young.
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
♪
[boy 1 grunts]
-[BOY 1, BOY 2] Yay!
-[BOY 3] Dang it!
I want a rematch!
[FERN] Mistress Frieren
is going to boil herself.
She's hardly left the hot spring
since we arrived.
And when she does come out,
it's only to visit magic shops.
She says we're staying
for two more days.
Well, that's a short stay
if we go by her timeline.
I made sure to give her
an earful.
Though, tomorrow,
we'll both be stuck here
without any plans.
No plans, huh?
Could be a good chance
to hit an armorer.
Need to get my axe sharpened.
As I said,
I'll be stuck with no plans.
[STARK] Hm?
Give me attention.
It wouldn't kill you to be
more considerate, Mr. Stark.
Come on, you could've
just asked nicely.
I mean, it's not like
I'm a mind reader.
She's always so hard on me.
So be it.
It's time to get some payback.
If you're so desperate
for my attention,
how about you and I
go on a date?
[STARK] Oops.
Yeah, I'm dead.
[Stark groaning]
[STARK] So long, cruel world.
[Stark gasps]
[FERN] Very well.
See you tomorrow.
[STARK] Your book.
Huh.
[STARK] Women are a mystery.
[footsteps]
[FRIEREN] Mm.
Mm?
[STARK] Hello?
[Stark sighs]
[Stark exclaims]
Frieren...
So, what do you think?
Is she plotting my murder
right now?
Am I dead meat or what?
It sounds bleak.
Bleaker still is the fact
you've come to me for advice.
You've gone mad.
[STARK] You're right.
Sorry for asking the impossible.
[FRIEREN] Who said anything
about impossible?
I'm a mature lady.
I know exactly how girls think.
[STARK] You mean it?
Then I'm trusting you.
I need you to be honest with me.
Frieren, pretend I asked you.
Are you happy or murderous?
Well, you've grown up
into a fine man, Stark.
I'm so happy, I might treat you
to a nice meal.
[STARK] Yeah, this isn't
helping at all.
It feels like I'm a kid
being forced to hang out
-with his grandma.
-[Frieren grunts]
You just called me a grandma.
That's offense two
after the hag slip.
I draw the line at three.
[STARK] You're counting?
Cut me some slack!
What exactly is gonna happen
when you "draw the line?"
I'll scream and cry.
My tantrums have struck fear
into the hearts of many.
They even caused Himmel the Hero
to tremble with terror.
[Frieren crying]
[continues crying]
[EISEN] She's been at it
for three days and three nights.
-My!
-Save us.
[STARK] That sounds awful.
What happened
to being a mature lady?
[Frieren wailing]
[Frieren sighs] A-ha!
Your problem is you lack
all tact and sensitivity.
[Stark sighs]
[FRIEREN] So, are you going
on this date or not?
I'd take it back,
but I think that would
only make things worse now.
It's fine.
I just need your help
to figure out
some places she would like.
I shouldn't have asked, huh?
Forget I said any--
Shall we take a look around?
[STARK] Huh?
[FRIEREN] Surely
I can find somewhere.
Somewhere she'd like.
-So, what should we do now?
-I could go for a snack.
[WOMAN 1] Me too!
You should start your date
at the market
and buy her
something fun to eat.
She's at her crankiest
when she's hungry.
The food stalls
could be a big hit.
Fern has loved snacking
ever since she was
a little girl.
♪
[FRIEREN] I would select a route
that includes shops
with pretty items like these.
Fern always likes baked goods,
but her cravings fluctuate
with her mood.
If you want to play it safe,
have a few dessert options
in your back pocket.
[BOTH] Mmm.
♪
What else is there?
[FRIEREN] A quiet plaza
like this would be nice.
I think she would
appreciate the view.
Thank you, Frieren.
You know Fern even better
than I thought you did.
I'm seriously impressed by you.
No, I don't know anything.
[STARK] Hm?
[FRIEREN]
Don't be impressed by me,
for Heiter
was the impressive one.
[STARK] Hm?
He studied little Fern
for years.
I'm merely the keeper
of his detailed record.
"She gets cranky
when she's hungry."
"Her appetite
is bigger than she is."
"She has an eye for beauty."
"Her preferences change
with her mood."
Everything I taught you
comes straight from Heiter.
He had lofty hopes for me.
It was evident
he wanted me to take up
the parental mantle
in his absence.
Some parent I became.
I know what he saw her like,
but I can't come up
with anything new.
♪
So what?
You remember every tiny detail
he gave you.
For what it's worth,
I think you're
a great parent to her.
You know,
this place feels familiar.
Reminds me of where we first
celebrated Fern's birthday
back when it was
just the two of us.
♪
[FRIEREN] I suppose you can be
rather thoughtful, Stark.
[Stark chuckles] About time.
[FRIEREN] I'll strike...
one offense from the record.
[STARK] Gee, thanks.
[footsteps]
I need some advice.
A boy asked me out on a date.
What should I do?
You've both gone mad.
[FERN] Hm?
Well, on with your concerns.
I was wondering,
have you ever been
on a date before?
I have.
'Course not.
Huh? Have you really?
Yes.
♪
[Fern sighs]
Who was it with?
And what exactly did you do?
Himmel and I tore apart
a whole village
looking for a lost cat.
We got the job from the owner
of the magic shop.
That just sounds like
business as usual to me.
Sorry, but...
I'm not sure that was a date.
Listen, Fern,
when close friends
of opposing sex
go out with just each other,
that is what
we grownups call a date.
[FERN] Mmm...
Right? That's what
my master said.
By that logic,
then I dated Sein, as well.
Just forget it.
[FRIEREN] Hm?
[soft rustling]
[FERN] Good night.
[Frieren snores]
♪
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[MALE GUARD]
Fern, the first-class mage.
-Right this way, Miss.
-[overlapping chatter]
[HEITER] I was certain
we were going to die.
[FRIEREN] Don't let
your guard down.
[HIMMEL] I want to protect
other people's homes, too.
EPISODE 32:
OTHER PEOPLE'S HOMES